E-mail: djalfo18@gmail.com

Career Summary

Alfonso is a systems engineer with more than three years of experience working for projects with Scrum and Kanban methodologies on software and web applications using React.js or Next.js. Alfonso's soft skills are orientation to results, problem solving and teamwork. More information about his professional profile on this link. He has experience in projects for digital media and entertainment, e-commerce B2C and B2B markets. More information about his portfolio and previous projects related to skills below on this link.

Summary of Qualifications

Proficient In:

React.js / Redux

- TypeScript
- JavaScript

Semantic UI

- HTML5 CSS3 / Sass
- Node.js / **Express** AWS S3

- Next.is
- Jira

- Python
- AEM

Git

SQL

Languages

- Spanish (native C2)
- English (upper intermediate- B2)

Portuguese (basic-A2)

Career History

GLOBANT, Bogota D.C., Colombia Phone number: +576014891340

Web UI Developer Semi-Senior Advanced Education market

- Collaborated to review and fix baseline documentation for software architecture team.
- Worked on proofs of concept (PoC) for different Translation Management Tools with internationalization (i18n) standards and principles and their integration with different microapps.
- Reviewed, approved and developed some changes to implement a laboratory app to perform different PoC for multi-lingual purposes.
- Performed manually and automatically different coverage assessments to know how many texts could be translated and how many translation keys are used.

Oct. 2020 - Dec. 2023

Apr. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Tools / Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Git, Node.js, NPM, Localazy, react-i18next, i18next-parser, Jira, Confluence, Microsoft Office 365, Miro.

Web UI Developer Semi-Senior Advanced Sep.2022 – Dec. 2022 Airlines market

- Solved different issues for breaking changes with new design systems and styled components for different B2B websites.
- Collaborated to fix some pipeline configuration issues on deployments for development and production environments.
- Worked on technical debt issues fixing unit tests for different artifacts increasing test coverage between 85% and 93% of statements in the last four months.

Tools/Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Git, Storybook, React Testing Library, Jest, Enzyme, Node.js, Express, NPM, Jfrog Artifactory, Jenkins, Jira, Grafana Loki

Web UI Developer Semi-Senior

Jan. 2021 - Aug. 2022

- E-commerce market
 - Developed user interfaces on front-end stack with Server-Side rendering.
 - Searched and provided Headless Content Management Systems solutions for specific development on an e-commerce website which was launched first time to production as a Minimum Viable Product for a client in June 2021.
 - Built and integrated Web pages and components with custom development for digital catalog.
 - Built and integrated a design system with atomic design patterns and custom web components.
 - Pull requested code and applied Control Versioning Systems, for example Gitlab, on repositories.
 - Built and run unit tests, so technical debt was solved fixing code issues and unit tests implementation, and updating snapshots on components, increasing the coverage until 60% to 70%
 - Participated in daily tasks and meetings, usability, information architecture and functionality by a Scrum agile methodology.
 - The digital store has sold more than \$5M USD on average between August and October 2021, and it had a conversion rate of 1.5% on Cyber Monday campaign in November 2021, 0.2% more than 2020.
 - Developed new features for different components to improve user experience on different landings and to increase conversion rates from web forms and other sources.
 - Integrated web services and API endpoints on Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) Single Page Application websites and modified some styles and scripts from frontend stack with React.js and TypeScript.

Tools/Technologies: React.js, Next.js, Strapi.js, Adobe Experience Manager, Redux, Thunk, RxJS, Sass, Semantic UI React, Stencil.js, Storybook, Gitlab, React Testing Library, Jest, React Test Renderer, SonarQube, Fortify, Figma, Miro, Mural, Jira, AWS S3, Postman, SwaggerHub

GRADIWEB S.A.S., Bogota D.C., Colombia

Phone number: +573163215113 / +573016306007

Web Developer

- Developed user interfaces on front-end and back-end stacks with Server-Side rendering.
- Searched and provided Content Management Systems solutions for specific development on an e-commerce website.
- Built and integrated Web pages and templates with custom development for forms and other HTML, CSS and DOM elements
- Participated in daily tasks, usability, information architecture and functionality.
- Made and provided a document about how to migrate a remote website to local host.

Tools/Technologies: PrestaShop 1.7, Smarty, WordPress, AdobeXD, Monday, Clockify, Trello

IDEAS INVERSION S.A.S., Bogota D.C., Colombia Phone number: +576012005122

June 2017 - Sep. 2017

Mar. 2020 - May 2020

Freelance Developer

- Developed and deployed a Web application on Google Cloud Platform using App Engine service.
- Used Cloud Storage service to manage Blade templates for views, images, and other binary files.
- Used and integrated some JavaScript libraries to make interactive and responsive design, visual dashboards and to generate PDF files on front-end stack.

Tools/Technologies: Laravel, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Google Charts

Education

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Bogota D.C., Colombia BS, Systems Engineering

Jan. 2006 - Apr. 2013